Every 2 ½, 3 months I’d go to the Philippines.
My partner there, Miss Mary,
Would have set up trips for me to different islands,
Like Cebu,
I was so upset at what happened, all the dead,
Cebu is one of the most beautiful places in the Philippines
And its people are known all over the country
When you say Cebu it means…
So, I’d go everywhere, interview people.
Mary was so clever,
she’d take advantage of the fact that I was going.
She’d buy ads there,
in the newspapers, the local radio, billboards.
Saying this man is coming from Lebanon
looking to interview girls
for jobs in Lebanon, Kuwait, Saudi Arabia, etc.
I’d be looking to recruit girls only for Lebanon!
But she was clever,
she’d make the most of it.
I’d arrive around 5 am,
get picked up from the airport, and…
it was shocking.
There’d be 500-600 people in the street,
they’d give them seats, talk to them through loudspeakers.
“The man just arrived.”
They’d take me up.
You’d feel….
I was really embarrassed by it.
All these women,
they’ll come up here one by one, to see you.
I had a desk set up,
a secretary outside,
Piles of papers.
I have a notebook…
I should give it to you someday.
I wrote down all these little things
about this situation.
Each woman would come in…
Imagine her feelings,
coming to prove how good she is,
how educated.
You’d see women…
this one’s a criminologist,
this one’s specialized in…
They were a hundred times more educated than me.
Coming to apply, to interview with me
for jobs as domestic workers.
The Philippines is a country with good education
good institutions,
intelligent, educated people,
but no job opportunities.