I went on a trip to India
The friend I work with there
brought me sacks full of passports
actual sacks
with several thousand passports
that he placed before me
Certainly it was about who paid him most
He’d come to the office in the morning
he had ash or drawings here
related to his religion
He’d be painted orange here
with a thing on his head
and take a seat
And the people who’d come see him
would trust him more
Like a Hajj here, who has a beard, prays
he took advantage of this in his work
So… he was quite ruthless
If a girl came to him wanting to travel today
and paid more than the girl
already waiting 20 days
she’d travel immediately
So we’d match up the girls…
this one with that person
this same one with someone else
They were all here
but each using another woman’s passport
So that the one who paid most, traveled first
And he had connections…
connections there at general security, the airport
everywhere related to the authorities
And he didn’t care
so long as he got paid